<resources>
    <string name="app_name">ScaffMate</string>

    <string name="search">Search Bar</string>
    <string name="search_bar_hint">Search Bar Hint</string>

    <string name="navigation_drawer_open">Open navigation drawer</string>
    <string name="navigation_drawer_close">Close navigation drawer</string>

    <string name="action_settings">Settings</string>

    <string name="about_us"> The people behind ScaffMate are dedicated to meeting the needs of scaffolders around Australia and New Zealand by providing an application that gives the user all the required knowledge needed on a scaffold site at their fingertips.\n

\nOur promise is to keep the content and useability of ScaffMate up to date making sure we are continually meeting the needs of our users.\n

\nWe encourage users to help us in achieving excellence by emailing ScaffMate before leaving any negative feedback so we can improve our application.


    </string>
    <string name="overview2"><b>Overview</b></string>

    <string name="overview">
        \nScaffMate is a complete scaffolding guide which has been developed in reference with safe work Australia’s online material. This app is a broad overview of all things scaffolding with an emphasis on risk management.\n

\nMaterial set within this application can be used to assist in all stages of scaffolding work. Covering topics such as Planning, Scaffold Duties, Types of Scaffold, Erect and Dismantling of Scaffold and Inspections and Maintenance Procedures. This Scaffolding app is really the complete guide to scaffolding safely and efficiently.\n</string>

    <string name="overview3">In the navigation side menu, you can find the complete scaffolding guide which holds all the content available on this application. Below the Complete Scaffolding Guide are the supervisor, leading hand and scaffolder categories which display topics specific to the roles responsibilities.\n</string>

    <string name="overview4">The ‘about us’ menu, is a brief description of who we (the developer) are and what we aim to achieve with this application.\n</string>

    \<string name="overview5">And Last but not least the ‘Contact us’ menu, is a direct email for you to provide feedback to the developer. We also encourage you to film/photograph your own unique solutions to your scaffolding problems and send them in with a brief description of the problem and the solution (what scaffolding method was used to solve the problem). We will upload them to the app.\n

\nThank you for downloading this app and we look forward to hearing your feedback on how we can make this app better.\n

\nWe encourage users to help us in achieving excellence by emailing ScaffMate before leaving any negative feedback so we can improve our application.</string>



    <string name="Risk_Manage_one"><b>1. Identify The Hazards</b>\n
        Find out what could cause harm. The following can help you identify potential hazards:</string>
    <string name="Risk_Manage_one1"> <b>&#8226; </b>  Observe the workplace to identify areas where scaffolds are used or scaffolding work is
performed and where there is interaction with vehicles, pedestrians and fixed structures.</string>

        <string name="Risk_Manage_one2"><b>&#8226; </b>  Look at the environment in which the scaffold is to be used including checking ground
conditions.</string>

    <string name="Risk_Manage_one3"><b>&#8226; </b>  Identify the major functional requirements of the scaffold like the maximum live and
dead loads and access requirements.</string>

    <string name="Risk_Manage_one4"><b>&#8226; </b>  Inspect the scaffolding before and after use.</string>

    <string name="Risk_Manage_one5"><b>&#8226; </b>  Ask your workers about any problems they encounter or anticipate at your workplace
when constructing or interacting with scaffolds and scaffolding work–consider
operation, inspection, maintenance, repair, transport and storage requirements.</string>

    <string name="Risk_Manage_one6"><b>&#8226; </b>  Inspect the erected scaffold.</string>

    <string name="Risk_Manage_one7"><b>&#8226; </b>  Review your incident and injury records including near misses.</string>

    <string name="Risk_Manage_two1"><b>2. Assess The Risks</b>\n
        Assess the risk. In many cases the risks and related control measures will be well known.
In other cases you may need to carry out a risk assessment to identify the likelihood
of somebody being harmed by the hazard and how serious the harm could be. A risk
assessment can help you determine what action you should take to control the risk and
how urgently the action needs to be taken.</string>

    <string name="Risk_Manage_three1"><b>3. Control The Risks</b>\n
        Take action to control the risk. The work health and safety laws require a business or
undertaking do all that is reasonably practicable to eliminate or minimise risks.
The ways of controlling risks are ranked from the highest level of protection and reliability
to the lowest. This ranking is known as the hierarchy of risk control. You must work through
this hierarchy to manage risks.
The first thing to consider is whether hazards can be completely removed from the
workplace. For example, risks can be eliminated by carrying out work at ground level
or on completed floors of a building.
If it is not reasonably practicable to completely eliminate the risk then consider the following
options in the order they appear below to minimise risks, so far as is reasonably practicable:</string>

    <string name="Risk_Manage_three2"><b>&#8226;  </b> substitute the hazard for something safer e.g. using mechanical aids like cranes, hoists,
pallet jacks or trolleys to move equipment and materials wherever possible instead of
manually lifting scaffolding</string>

    <string name="Risk_Manage_three3"><b>&#8226;  </b> isolate the hazard from people e.g. install concrete barriers to separate pedestrians
and powered mobile plant from scaffolds to minimise the risk of collision, and</string>

    <string name="Risk_Manage_three4"><b>&#8226;  </b> use engineering controls e.g. provide toeboards, perimeter containment sheeting
or overhead protective structures to prevent objects falling hitting workers or other
people below the work area.</string>

    <string name="Risk_Manage_three5">If after implementing the above control measures a risk still remains, consider the
following controls in the order below to minimise the remaining risk, so far as is reasonably
practicable:</string>

     <string name="Risk_Manage_three6"><b>&#8226;  </b> use administrative controls e.g. storing scaffolding as close as practical to the work area
to minimise the distance over which loads are manually moved, and</string>

     <string name="Risk_Manage_three7"><b>&#8226;  </b> use personal protective equipment (PPE) e.g. hard hats, protective hand and footwear
and high visibility vests.</string>

     <string name="Risk_Manage_three8">A combination of the controls set out above may be used if a single control is not enough
to minimise the risks. You need to consider all possible control measures and make a decision about which
are reasonably practicable for your workplace. Deciding what is reasonably practicable
includes the availability and suitability of control measures, with a preference for using
substitution, isolation or engineering controls to minimise risks before using administrative
controls or PPE. Cost may also be relevant, but you can only consider this after all other
factors have been taken into account.</string>

    <string name="Risk_Manage_four1"><b>4. Review Controls</b>\n
        Check your control measures regularly to ensure they are working as planned. Control
measures need to be regularly reviewed to make sure they remain effective, taking into
consideration any changes, the nature and duration of work and that the system is working
as planned.\n
    \n© Commonwealth of Australia 2014.</string>
    <string name="Duty_Holder_one1">A person conducting a business or undertaking has the primary
duty to ensure, so far as is reasonably practicable, workers and
other people are not exposed to health and safety risks arising
from the business or undertaking.
This duty requires the person to manage risks by eliminating health
and safety risks so far as is reasonably practicable, and if it is not
reasonably practicable to eliminate the risks, by minimising those
risks so far as is reasonably practicable. It also includes ensuring
so far as is reasonably practicable the:</string>

    <string name="Duty_Holder_one2"><b>&#8226;  </b> provision and maintenance of safe scaffolding and scaffolds</string>

    <string name="Duty_Holder_one3"><b>&#8226;  </b> safe erection, alteration, dismantling and use of scaffolds, and</string>

    <string name="Duty_Holder_one4"><b>&#8226;  </b> safe use, handling, storage and transport of scaffolding.</string>

    <string name="Duty_Holder_one5">The WHS Regulations include specific duties for a person
    conducting a business or undertaking with management or control
    of scaffolding plant, powered mobile plant and plant that lifts or
    suspends loads.</string>

    <string name="Duty_Holder_two">Designers, manufacturers, importers and suppliers of scaffolding
    or scaffolds must ensure, so far as is reasonably practicable, the
    plant or structure they design, manufacture, import or supply
    is without risks to health and safety. This duty includes carrying
    out analysis, testing or an examination and providing specific
    information about the plant. Information must, so far as is
    reasonably practicable, be passed on from the designer through
    to the manufacturer and supplier to the end user.</string>

    <string name="Duty_Holder_three">People installing, constructing or commissioning scaffolding
or scaffolds must ensure, so far as is reasonably practicable, all
workplace activity relating to the plant or structure including its
decommissioning or dismantling is without risks to health or safety.</string>

     <string name="Duty_Holder_three1">In this Guide the scaffolding contractor is the person responsible for
installing, constructing and commissioning scaffolds.</string>

     <string name="Duty_Holder_four">Officers, such as company directors, have a duty to exercise due
diligence to ensure the business or undertaking complies with the
WHS Act and Regulations. This includes taking reasonable steps
to ensure the business or undertaking has and uses appropriate
resources and processes to eliminate or minimise risks from plant.</string>

     <string name="Duty_Holder_five">Workers and other people at the workplace must take reasonable
care for their own health and safety, co-operate with reasonable
policies, procedures and instructions and not adversely affect other
people’s health and safety.\n

     \n© Commonwealth of Australia 2014.</string>

    <string name="Who_is_Involved1"><b>Who is Involved</b>\n
        \nYou must consult your workers and their health and safety representatives (if any) when
deciding how to manage the risks of scaffolds and scaffolding work.\n

        \n If there is more than one business or undertaking involved at your workplace you must
consult them to find out who is doing what and work together so risks are eliminated or
minimised, so far as is reasonably practicable. \n

       \n This may involve discussing workplace-specific requirements including the type of scaffold
to be erected, the scaffolding to be used and what training is required for workers
particularly if a scaffolding high risk work licence is not required.\n

    \n© Commonwealth of Australia 2014.</string>


    <string name="Comp_Lic1">A person who erects, alters or dismantles any scaffold must be competent to do the
work safely. \n
\n A person undertaking scaffolding work must hold the relevant class of scaffolding high risk
work licence as required by the WHS Regulations. The scaffolding high risk work licence
classes are: \n

\n<b>Basic scaffolding licence—required for scaffolding work involving:</b> \n
<b>&#8226;  </b> modular or prefabricated scaffolds \n
<b>&#8226;  </b> cantilevered materials hoists with a maximum working load of 500 kilograms \n
        <b>&#8226;  </b> ropes \n
        <b>&#8226;  </b> gin wheels \n
<b>&#8226;  </b> fall arrest systems including safety nets and static lines, and \n
<b>&#8226;  </b> bracket scaffolds (tank and formwork). \n
 \n<b>Intermediate scaffolding licence—required for scaffolding work involving:</b> \n
 <b>&#8226;  </b> cantilevered crane loading platforms \n
 <b>&#8226;  </b> cantilevered scaffolds \n
 <b>&#8226;  </b> spur scaffolds \n
 <b>&#8226;  </b> barrow ramps and sloping platforms \n
 <b>&#8226;  </b> scaffolding associated with perimeter safety screens and shutters \n
 <b>&#8226;  </b> mast climbing work platforms, and \n
 <b>&#8226;  </b> tube and coupler scaffolds including tube and coupler covered ways and gantries. \n
 \n<b>Advanced scaffolding licence—required for scaffolding work involving:</b> \n
 <b>&#8226;  </b> cantilevered hoists \n
 <b>&#8226;  </b> hung scaffolds including scaffolds hung from tubes, wire ropes or chains, and \n
 <b>&#8226;  </b> suspended scaffolds. \n
\n Where a person undertakes construction work they must have successfully completed
general construction induction training. \n
\n A person who erects, alters or dismantles a scaffold where there is a risk of a person or
object falling four metres or less from the platform or structure does not require a high
risk work licence. This sort of work may involve tasks like erecting a small frame scaffold to
repair the eaves of a house or to paint a ceiling. These types of scaffolds are not generally
used to provide a work platform at a height in excess of one storey or for use by many
workers at once.\n
    \n© Commonwealth of Australia 2014.</string>

    <string name="b4_start_scaff_work1"><b>Choosing The Scaffold</b>\n
        A primary objective of scaffold planning and design is to prevent scaffold collapse before,
during and after placement of the scaffold. The collapse of a scaffold can cause death or
significant injury to workers or passers-by and damage to structures. \n

    \nManaging the risks associated with scaffolds and scaffolding work begins when you first
start making decisions about how scaffolds are going to be used at a workplace and what
type of scaffold will be best and safest for the job.</string>

     <string name="b4_start_scaff_work2"><b>Designing The Scaffold</b>\n
         The first step in controlling the identified risks should be at the design stage where the
focus is on eliminating risks through good design of:\n
\n<b>&#8226;  </b>scaffolding—the Act classifies these individual components as “plant”\n
\n<b>&#8226;  </b>the scaffold—the Act classifies this as a “structure” that is covered by both Parts 5 and
6 of the WHS Regulations, and\n
\n<b>&#8226;  </b>work systems and processes for the safe erection, alteration and dismantling of the scaffold.
     </string>

    <string name="b4_start_scaff_work3"><b>The Scaffolding Plant</b>\n
        Scaffolding designers have a duty to design scaffolding that is safe to manufacture,
assemble and use for the purpose it was designed for. They design the scaffolding system.
The scaffolding may be purchased, hired in or supplied, for example by a scaffolding
contractor.</string>

     <string name="b4_start_scaff_work4"><b>The Scaffold Structure</b>\n

         The scaffold designer will be responsible for selecting the appropriate scaffolding and
preparing a scaffold design for the job. They design the scaffold installation.
The scaffold designer should consider:\n
\n<b>&#8226;  </b>the intended use of the scaffold\n
\n<b>&#8226;  </b>hazards and risks for people who erect, dismantle, use or are near the scaffold\n
\n<b>&#8226;  </b>the foundations including ground conditions\n
\n<b>&#8226;  </b>the load bearing capacity of the surface where the scaffold is to be erected or the
suspension systems for hung or suspended scaffolds\n
\n<b>&#8226;  </b>dead loads e.g. resulting from the size and weight of the scaffold\n
\n<b>&#8226;  </b>live loads e.g. workers, plant and material on the scaffold\n
\n<b>&#8226;  </b>environmental loads e.g. wind loads\n
\n<b>&#8226;  </b>bracing, tying and anchors—where anchors will be placed on the supporting structure
and types of anchors to be used\n
\n<b>&#8226;  </b>supporting structures\n
\n<b>&#8226;  </b>edge protection\n
\n<b>&#8226;  </b>protection against falls and falling objects\n
\n<b>&#8226;  </b>containment sheeting, and\n
\n<b>&#8226;  </b>safe entry and exit.\n

\nWhere necessary, improved scaffold stability may be achieved by:\n

\n<b>&#8226;  </b>tying the scaffold to a supporting structure\n
\n<b>&#8226;  </b>guying to a supporting structure\n
\n<b>&#8226;  </b>increasing the dead load by securely attaching counterweights near the base, and\n
\n<b>&#8226;  </b>adding bays to increase the base dimension.\n

\nScaffolds should be designed by a competent person, for example a person holding a
relevant scaffolding high risk work licence.
     </string>

    <string name="b4_start_scaff_work5"><b>The System of Work</b>\n
        Systems of work should be clear but flexible to meet changing circumstances as the work
progresses. The system of work should provide for the assessment and control of any new
risks arising from proposed changes to the work before they are implemented.\n

\nA documented safe system of work is an administrative control. For scaffolding work this
could include consideration of:\n

\n<b>&#8226;  </b>worker competency and licensing requirements\n
\n<b>&#8226;  </b>consultation and coordination of the work with others\n
\n<b>&#8226;  </b>access and exit\n
\n<b>&#8226;  </b>exclusion zones\n
\n<b>&#8226;  </b>permit-to-work systems\n
\n<b>&#8226;  </b>fall arrest systems\n
\n<b>&#8226;  </b>inspection and maintenance\n
\n<b>&#8226;  </b>emergency arrangements, and\n
\n<b>&#8226;  </b>changes to the work arrangements.\n

        \n© Commonwealth of Australia 2014.
    </string>

     <string name="document1"><b>Competancy and Licensing</b>\n
         A range of documentation may be required depending on the scaffolding and scaffold.
For example, prefabricated scaffolding requires plant design registration. The construction
of a scaffold where a person can fall more than two metres will generally require a Safe
Work Method Statement (SWMS) for construction work.\n

     \n<b>Designer’s Safety Report for Construction Work</b>\n
         Most erecting and dismantling of a scaffold is construction work as it involves the
construction of a structure or is undertaken at a construction workplace.\n

\nA designer must prepare a safety report for a specific or unusual scaffold designs but not
for common scaffold designs where the risks are already known. For example, a design
specifying an unusual base structure that has to be erected to support the scaffold may
introduce unique hazards and risk controls.\n

\nThe person commissioning the construction work must consult with the designer of the
whole or any part of the structure about eliminating and controlling risks. The general duty
to provide information under the WHS Act may be met through the designer’s safety report
prepared under Chapter 6 of the WHS Regulations for construction work.\n

\nA designer’s written safety report may include proprietary documentation setting out
how to use the scaffolding or scaffolding system to safely erect a scaffold. Where there is a
principal contractor for a construction project, the person who commissioned the scaffold
design must give a copy of the relevant designer’s safety report to the principal contractor.\n

    \n<b>Safe Work Method Statement for Construction</b>\n
         Erecting a scaffold or work on a scaffold may involve activities defined as high risk
construction work under the WHS Regulations.\n

\nHigh risk construction work includes any construction work where there is a risk of
a person falling more than two metres. Scaffolding work is defined with a four metre
threshold for licensing purposes. This means in some cases a high risk work licence may not
be required to erect a scaffold—because it is less than four metres—but there
may still be need for a SWMS because it is more than two metres.\n

\nHigh risk construction work also includes work which:\n

\n<b>&#8226;  </b>involves structural alterations or repairs that require temporary support to
prevent collapse\n
\n<b>&#8226;  </b>is carried out on or near energised electrical installations or services, and\n
\n<b>&#8226;  </b>is carried out in an area at a workplace in which there is movement of powered
mobile plant.\n

         \nA SWMS must be prepared for high risk construction work before the work starts.
The SWMS must:\n

\n<b>&#8226;  </b>identify the type of high risk construction work being done\n
\n<b>&#8226;  </b>specify the health and safety hazards and risks arising from the work\n
\n<b>&#8226;  </b>describe how the risks will be controlled, and\n
\n<b>&#8226;  </b>describe how the control measures are to be implemented, monitored and reviewed.\n

\nThe SWMS must be developed in consultation with workers and their representatives
who are carrying out the high risk construction work.\n


    \n<b>Scaffolding Plan</b>\n
        Where required, a SWMS will set out the work method to safely erect, use and dismantle
a scaffold. Where a SWMS is not required a scaffolding plan will help identify ways to
protect people who are:\n

\n<b>&#8226;  </b>erecting, using, maintaining, altering and dismantling the scaffold, and\n
\n<b>&#8226;  </b>near the scaffold or scaffolding work e.g. other workers and members of the public.\n

         \nFor more complex scaffolds a scaffolding plan should be prepared by a competent person.
In preparing a scaffolding plan the person should consult with a range of other people
relevant to the work and workplace, for example:\n

\n<b>&#8226;  </b>the scaffold designer e.g. to discuss the design loads and the capability of the structure
to support extra loadings\n
\n<b>&#8226;  </b>the scaffolding contractor or builder—this may be the person conducting a business or
undertaking or a principal contractor—e.g. to assess where underground drains or pits
and underground services are located. The work should be planned to avoid excavating
service trenches under, through or adjacent to scaffolds\n
\n<b>&#8226;  </b>workers, work health and safety committees and health and safety representatives
regarding erecting, maintaining, altering and dismantling the scaffold\n
\n<b>&#8226;  </b>other competent people familiar with similar structures e.g. an engineer or a person
holding an intermediate or advanced scaffolding high risk work licence, and\n
\n<b>&#8226;  </b>the electricity supply authority if the scaffold is being erected near overhead electric lines.\n

        \nThe scaffolding plan should include a site layout plan and detail the elevations and sections
of the scaffold. It should be kept at the workplace if reasonably practicable, or be readily
accessible near the scaffold should it be required. The scaffolding plan should address:\n

        \n<b>&#8226;  </b>basis of design\n
\n<b>&#8226;  </b>type of scaffold\n
\n<b>&#8226;  </b>foundations including ground conditions\n
\n<b>&#8226;  </b>the weight bearing capacity of the surface where the scaffold is to be erected\n
\n<b>&#8226;  </b>dead loads e.g. resulting from the size and weight of the scaffold\n
\n<b>&#8226;  </b>live and environmental loads e.g. wind loads\n
\n<b>&#8226;  </b>containment sheeting\n
\n<b>&#8226;  </b>supporting structures\n
\n<b>&#8226;  </b>entry and exit\n
        \n<b>&#8226;  </b>tying and anchors—where anchors will be placed on the supporting structure and types
of anchors to be used\n
\n<b>&#8226;  </b>bracing, and\n
\n<b>&#8226;  </b>edge protection.\n

    \n<b>WHS Management Plan</b>\n
         Where the cost of the construction work is $250 000 or more a principal contractor for
a construction project must:\n

\n<b>&#8226;  </b>take all reasonable steps to obtain a copy of the SWMS relating to the work from each
person conducting a business or undertaking carrying out the high risk construction
work before the work starts, and\n
\n<b>&#8226;  </b>prepare a written WHS management plan for the workplace before work on the
construction project starts.\n

         \nA WHS management plan must include:\n

\n<b>&#8226;  </b>a list of people who have health and safety responsibilities, and\n
\n<b>&#8226;  </b>arrangements for consulting workers, managing incidents that occur and any site
specific health and safety rules.\n

   \n<b>Plant Design Registration</b>\n
        Prefabricated scaffolding is defined as an integrated system of prefabricated components
manufactured in such a way that the geometry of assembled scaffolds is pre-determined.
Prefabricated scaffolding can include modular, tower, cantilever, hung and suspended
(swing-stage) scaffolds.\n

\nPrefabricated scaffolding must be design registered as required under Part 1 of Schedule 5
of the WHS Regulations.\n

\nThe person with management or control of the prefabricated scaffolding must ensure
the design registration number is kept where it is readily accessible. If you are hiring
prefabricated scaffolding, the supplier must provide the design registration number, usually
on the supply docket or agreement.\n

         \n<b>Emergency Plan</b>\n
        An emergency plan must be prepared and maintained so it remains effective for the
workplace. The emergency plan should provide for emergency response, evacuation
procedures, medical treatment and assistance, and communication with emergency service
organisations and others at the workplace. For example, emergency contact numbers
should be displayed where they can be easily seen.\n

\nWorkers must be provided with information and training on the emergency procedures for
the workplace and the procedures must be tested.\n

\nResponses to an emergency should be coordinated. The scaffolding contractor should
consult with the principal contractor who prepares the broader workplace emergency plan,
so unexpected incidents, for example scaffold collapse or people falling from height are
included in the broader emergency plan.\n

\nEmergency arrangements for evacuating an injured worker from, for example a multilevel
perimeter screened scaffold should consider how to safely remove an immobilised or
unconscious person. This may include creating emergency access points through screens
and decks.\n

     \n© Commonwealth of Australia 2014.</string>

<string name="com_haz1">\n<b>Adjacent Building and Structures</b>\n
    \nNo part of the scaffolding work should adversely affect the structural integrity of other
buildings. You should ensure risks are controlled to prevent injury to people or damage
to adjacent buildings or structures from the:\n

    \n<b>&#8226;  </b>collapse of the scaffold onto an adjacent building or structure, and\n
    \n<b>&#8226;  </b>collapse of an adjacent building or structure, or a part of a building or structure due
    to scaffolding work or related activities.\n

    \n© Commonwealth of Australia 2014.

</string>

    <string name="com_haz2">\n<b>Electric Power Lines</b>\n
        Electric lines whether overhead or underground can be a significant hazard. Construction
work carried out on or near energised electrical installations or services is high risk
construction work and a SWMS must be prepared before this work starts.\n

        \nThis Information Sheet provides advice on managing the risks of erecting, dismantling and using fixed scaffolding near overhead
electric lines and associated electrical equipment with an operating voltage up to and including 33,000 volts.\n

        \nWhere the operating voltage of the overhead electric lines is above 33,000 volts you should
consult the Electricity Supply Authority and comply with all special conditions imposed
by them.\n

        \n<b>What are the risks?</b>\n

\nContact with energised overhead electric
lines by erecting, dismantling and using
fixed scaffolding can cause death, electric
shock or other injury to plant operators
and workers. This can be caused directly or
indirectly by electricity—a close approach
to line conductors may allow a ‘flashover’ to
occur. The risk of flashover increases as the
line voltage increases.\n

        \n<b>What do I need to do?</b>\n

\nYou must manage the risks associated with
scaffolding work near energised overhead
electric lines and associated electrical
equipment by:
\n<b>&#8226;  </b> identifying potential hazards
\n<b>&#8226;  </b> consulting workers and asset owners e.g.
the Electricity Supply Authority or the
person with management or control of
the electric line or premises, and
\n<b>&#8226;  </b> deciding what work zones and approach
distances are required for safe operations.\n

        \n<b>When assessing the risks consider:</b>\n

\n<b>&#8226;  </b> the location, height, arrangement and
visibility of overhead electric lines and
supporting structures e.g. poles, towers
and stay wires
\n<b>&#8226;  </b> the voltage of electric lines and exposed
energised parts and whether they are
insulated or bare
\n<b>&#8226;  </b> possible sway or sag of the electric lines
\n<b>&#8226;  </b> the scaffold’s dimensions and operating
characteristics including inherent stability
\n<b>&#8226;  </b> conductivity if the scaffolds are earthed
\n<b>&#8226;  </b> the minimum clearance distance from the
closest part of the scaffold or plant being
used to the electric lines
\n<b>&#8226;  </b> erecting and dismantling scaffolding
\n<b>&#8226;  </b> the type of work activities required and
the frequency of work tasks
\n<b>&#8226;  </b> qualifications, competency, skill and
experience of people doing the work, and
\n<b>&#8226;  </b> safe work practices and procedures e.g.
a safety observer and ‘permit to work’.\n

        \n<b>Approach distances</b>\n
\nAS/NZS 4576:1995: Guidelines for scaffolding
sets a 4 metre approach distance for metallic
scaffolding used near overhead electric lines.\n

\nWhen planning scaffolding work you should
use 4 metres initially and then consider other
factors that may require a greater approach
distance including:
\n<b>&#8226;  </b> the proximity of overhead electric lines
\n<b>&#8226;  </b> the proximity and operating radius of
vehicles, cranes and other moving plant
\n<b>&#8226;  </b> environmental conditions e.g. storm
activity, wind strength and direction,
heavy rain, ice, hail and lightning, and
\n<b>&#8226;  </b> entry and exit for workers, materials
and plant.\n

\nThe 4 metre or greater approach distance
applies in any direction where metallic
scaffold is erected, used or dismantled near
overhead electric lines.\n

\nIf there is a risk the 4 metre approach (see
Figure 1) distance cannot be maintained
you should contact the Electricity Supply
Authority to determine a safe system of
work for the erection, use and dismantling
of the scaffolding.\n

        \n© Commonwealth of Australia 2014.

</string>

    <string name="com_haz3">\nElectric lines should always be treated as
energised unless you have:\n


\n<b>&#8226;  </b> an access authority confirming the electric
lines have been de-energised, or
\n<b>&#8226;  </b> another written document from the
Electricity Supply Authority which allows
people to work in the No Go Zone.\n

\nThe presence, location, type and operating
voltage of all overhead electric lines should be
verified by a competent person, for example
an electrical engineer.\n

        \n<b>How do I control the risks?</b>\n

\nThe best way to eliminate the hazard is by
preventing people, plant, equipment and
materials from coming close enough to
energised overhead electric lines for direct
contact or ‘flashover’ to occur. Consider:\n

\n<b>&#8226;  </b> de-energising the electric line\n
\n<b>&#8226;  </b> isolating and earthing the line for the
duration of the work\n
\n<b>&#8226;  </b> re-routing the electric line away from
the scaffolding after consultation and
agreement of the Electricity Supply
Authority, or\n
\n<b>&#8226;  </b> replacing existing overhead electric lines
with underground electric cables.\n

\nDe-energising or moving electric lines should
be arranged with the Electricity Supply
Authority as soon as possible.\n

\nWhere elimination is not reasonably
practicable, minimise the risks by substituting
the hazard or work practice with something
safer, for example by:\n

        \n<b>&#8226;  </b> using alternative plant that cannot enter
an unsafe zone, or\n
\n<b>&#8226;  </b> using non-conductive tools.\n

\nConsider isolating the hazard from people by
erecting a physical barrier on the scaffold to
prevent a person, anything attached to the
person or anything held by the person from
entering the specified approach distance or:\n

\nUse engineering controls like:\n

\n<b>&#8226;  </b> substituting the scaffold with an elevated
work platform, or\n
\n<b>&#8226;  </b> using an insulated fibreglass handle on
a paint roller instead of a conductive
aluminium extension handle when
standing on scaffolding.\n

\nIf a risk still remains use administrative
controls like:\n

\n<b>&#8226;  </b> a safety observer to warn people before
they enter the 4 metre approach distance\n
\n<b>&#8226;  </b> arranging for the Electricity Supply
Authority to identify exposed energised
low voltage conductors, up to and
including 1000 volts and fitting them with
approved visual indicators\n
\n<b>&#8226;  </b> making hazards more visible by using
approved visual indicators e.g. tiger tails.\n

\nIn this situation:\n

\n<b>&#8226;  </b> tiger tails should be installed for the
full length of the scaffolding plus a
minimum distance of 5 metres beyond
each end of the scaffolding\n

\n<b>&#8226;  </b> a competent person should visually
inspect the tiger tails each day before
starting scaffolding operations, and\n
\n<b>&#8226;  </b> if the tiger tails have moved or have
been damaged, the Electricity Supply
Authority should be contacted so
they are replaced or relocated in the
correct position.\n

\nConsultation with the Electricity Supply
Authority will confirm the owner of the
electric line and costs associated with the
installation and application of tiger tails.\n

\nNote: Tiger tails do not provide protection
against mechanical interference or electrical
hazards. Using tiger tails does not allow
workers to enter the 4 metre approach
distance.\n

\nAlso consider the use of personal protective
equipment (PPE) including:\n

\n<b>&#8226;  </b> electrically tested insulating gloves, rubber
soled boots and safety helmets\n
        \n<b>&#8226;  </b> rubber insulating mats or on an
equipotential conductive mat for workers
to stand on, and\n
\n<b>&#8226;  </b> dry clothes especially in wet or humid
conditions.\n

\nA combination of the above controls can
be used if a single control is not enough
to minimise the risks.\n

\n<b>Extra control measures
for electrical wires passing
through a scaffold</b>\n

\nWhere low voltage electrical wires or equipment
pass through a scaffold they should be:\n

\n<b>&#8226;  </b> de-energised for the duration of the work,
or\n
\n<b>&#8226;  </b> fully enclosed to meet the Electricity Supply
Authority’s requirements using a non-conductive material
e.g. moisture resistant flooring grade
particleboard, dry timber, dry plywood or
similar material or plastic piping approved
by the Electricity Supply Authority.\n

        \n<b>Erected scaffolding using
a hoarding and enclosure
for reduced safety clearances</b>\n

\nA hoarding is containment sheeting fixed to the
external face of a scaffold to form a physical
barrier between workers and overhead electric
lines and associated electrical equipment.\n

\nFigure 4 shows the horizontal safety distances
(A) and vertical mechanical clearances (B) from
electrical conductors required by Electricity
Supply Authorities.\n

\nYou should check the clearance distances
before erecting any scaffolding near overhead
electric lines. An electrical engineer can provide
the safety clearance distances used to design
the scaffolding and control the risks. Clearance
distances must be maintained.\n

\nThe following installation conditions apply:\n

\n<b>&#8226;  </b> gaps between fitted sheets of plywood do
not exceed 3 mm\n
\n<b>&#8226;  </b> no exposed cut or drilled holes in the sheets
of plywood\n
\n<b>&#8226;  </b> the scaffolder uses non-conductive means
to attach the plywood to the scaffold and
ensures the arrangement can withstand the
wind load, and\n
        \n<b>&#8226;  </b> signs should be attached to the safe side
of the hoarding warning of the electrical
hazard and that the hoarding must not
be removed.\n

\nEnsure a competent person visually inspects
the hoarding and the enclosure daily to
ensure they are in a satisfactory condition
and remain impenetrable.\n

\n<b>Safe work method statements
(SWMS)</b>\n

\nA SWMS is required for energised electrical
work and high risk construction work
carried out on or near energised electrical
installations or services. A written SWMS
should be based on a risk assessment.
The SWMS and risk assessment should be
available to workers on site for the duration
of the work.\n

        \n© Commonwealth of Australia 2014.

</string>

     <string name="com_haz4"><b>Entry and Exits</b>\n
         Safe entry and exit is required for workers when erecting, using and dismantling a scaffold.
Common means of entry and exit include:\n

\n<b>&#8226;  </b> temporary stairs or ladder access systems installed at the start of erection and
progressed with the scaffold\n
\n<b>&#8226;  </b> permanently installed platforms or ramps e.g. part of an adjacent building\n
\n<b>&#8226;  </b> personnel hoists—non-mechanical forms of exit e.g. a ladder or stair tower should be
provided in case of emergency, and\n
\n<b>&#8226;  </b> the existing floor level of a building if entry from there is safe.\n

\nStairs should be secured to the scaffold bay. If stairs cannot be self-secured to the
scaffold they should be lashed. If not secured the designer or supplier should provide
documentation showing the maximum amount of clearance allowed between the transom
and the top and bottom of the stair module. The gap between the end of a stair module
and a transom should be as small as possible. Large gaps can lead to stairs dislodging
and falling when a load is placed onto it.\n

     \n© Commonwealth of Australia 2014.
     </string>

 <string name="com_haz5"><b>Falls</b>\n
     A risk to health and safety associated with a fall by a person from one level to another that
is reasonably likely to cause injury to the person or any other person must be managed.
Hazards that may increase the risk of falls include:\n

\n<b>&#8226;  </b> poor environmental conditions like:\n
\n<b>(a)  </b> strong winds that may cause workers to lose balance
\n<b>(b)  </b> rain causing slippery work surfaces
\n<b>(c)  </b> glare emitted from work surfaces or poor lighting affecting visibility\n

\n<b>&#8226;  </b> materials, equipment or protruding objects below or in adjoining work areas like:\n
\n<b>(a)  </b> pallets of construction materials
\n<b>(b)  </b> vertical reinforcing steel
\n<b>(c)  </b> rubbish skips
\n<b>(d)  </b> exposed starter bars
\n<b>(e)  </b> large tools\n

\n<b>&#8226;  </b> void areas not identified or protected e.g. ladder access voids\n
\n<b>&#8226;  </b> incomplete scaffolds or loose scaffolding in areas where work is being done or is likely
to be done, and\n
\n<b>&#8226;  </b> inadequate training, instruction and supervision of scaffold workers.\n

\nPassive engineering controls like handrails and edge protection can minimise the risk of
a fall during work at height. Catch platforms can be used to minimise the distance a person
could fall during work at height and also to catch falling objects.\n

     \nFall arrest systems should only be used during the following scaffold activities:\n

\n<b>&#8226;  </b> Erecting or dismantling drop or hung scaffolds where the scaffold is constructed from
top to bottom—this allows for a clear fall zone in the event of a fall.\n
\n<b>&#8226;  </b> Fixing and removing trolley tracks on suspension rigs.\n
\n<b>&#8226;  </b> Erecting or dismantling cantilevered needles and decking between the needles.
Fall arrest systems could also be used when the first lift of scaffold is erected where
workers are standing on the deck between the needles.\n
\n<b>&#8226;  </b> Erecting and dismantling the first lift of a cantilevered scaffold including the first platform.\n
\n<b>&#8226;  </b> Attaching and removing spurs projecting from the supporting structure.\n

 \n© Commonwealth of Australia 2014.
 </string>

     <string name="com_haz6"><b>Falling Objects</b>\n
         Falling object risk control measures include fall arrest platforms, overhead protective
structures, perimeter containment screens and exclusion zones to eliminate or minimise
the risk of falling objects.\n

\nPerimeter containment screens can be made of mesh, high quality shade cloth, timber,
plywood, metal sheeting or other suitable material. Before using perimeter containment
screening, consider other risks like conductivity of electricity and additional dead and live
loads. For example, the extra wind loading on the scaffold should be considered when
selecting a screening material and the framework supporting a screen must be able to
support loads resulting from the screen.\n

\nPerimeter containment screens should be located inside the standards on working
platforms or in accordance with the manufacturer’s specifications. Where used, the lining
should be attached to the inside of the mesh.\n

\nThe scaffold design and its ties fitted with containment sheeting should be approved
by a competent person, for example an engineer with experience in structural design.\n

     \n© Commonwealth of Australia 2014.</string>

     <string name="com_haz7"><b>Ladders</b>\n
         Ladders may be used where entry to the working platform is needed by only a few people
and where tools and equipment can be delivered separately to the working platform, for
example by materials hoist, crane or a rope and gin wheel. Ladders used for entry to or
exit from a scaffold should be:\n

\n<b>&#8226;  </b> fixed industrial single ladders—not extensions ladders\n
\n<b>&#8226;  </b> located within a separate ladder access bay of the scaffold wherever space permits, and\n
\n<b>&#8226;  </b> set up on a firm, level surface, be securely fixed and not used on scaffold bays to gain
extra height above the scaffold structure.\n

\nIf the access bay is part of the working platform a trap door should be provided. Ladder
entry should be far enough away from the working platform where possible to prevent
people falling through openings. Engineering controls and safe work procedures should
be implemented so that the trap door remains closed while working from the platform.
Platforms should also allow correct use of ladders, for example a person passing through
the trap door should not need to hold it open. Gates should be self-closing and not open
away from the platform.\n

\nLadders should not be used as a work platform or to gain extra height to carry out work
from a scaffold.\n

     \n© Commonwealth of Australia 2014.</string>

    <string name="com_haz8"><b>Ground Conditions</b>\n
        Ground conditions should be stable and those doing the scaffolding work should be
aware of any factors that may affect ground stability before the scaffold is erected or
during its use.\n

\nGround conditions should be assessed by a competent person to check the ground is
stable and able to bear the most adverse combination of dead, live and environmental
loads that can reasonably be expected during the period the scaffold is to be erected and
dismantled and while it is in use.\n

\nWater and nearby excavations may lead to ground subsidence and the collapse of a
scaffold. Any likely watercourse, for example a recently filled trench that has the potential
to create a wash out under the scaffold base should be diverted away from the scaffold.

    \n© Commonwealth of Australia 2014.</string>

    <string name="com_haz9"><b>Loading</b>\n
        \nA scaffold should be designed for the most adverse combination of dead and live loads
that can reasonably be expected during the period the scaffold is in use.\n

\nDead loads relate to the self-weight of the scaffold structure and scaffolding including:\n
\n<b>&#8226;  </b> working, catch or access platforms\n
\n<b>&#8226;  </b> stairways, ladders, screens and sheeting\n
\n<b>&#8226;  </b> platform brackets, suspension ropes, secondary ropes, traversing ropes and tie
assemblies, and\n
\n<b>&#8226;  </b> hoists and electrical cables.\n

\nLive loads include the:\n

\n<b>&#8226;  </b> weight of people\n
\n<b>&#8226;  </b> weight of materials and debris\n
\n<b>&#8226;  </b> weight of tools and equipment\n
\n<b>&#8226;  </b> environmental loads e.g. wind, rain, and\n
\n<b>&#8226;  </b> impact forces.\n

\nThe specifications of the designer, manufacturer or supplier should be followed for the
maximum loads of the scaffold. The dead and live loads should be calculated during the
design stage to ensure the supporting structure and the lower standards are capable of
supporting the loads that will be applied at the workplace.\n

\nIf the scaffold is to be altered at the workplace, consider any new loads that may apply and
consult the scaffold designer. For example, wind and rain loads may increase if perimeter
containment, shade cloth or signs are attached to the scaffold. Staggering the joints in
standards may help control the risk of scaffold collapse from additional environmental loads.\n

\nScaffolds should not be used to support formwork and plant, for example hoist towers and
concrete pumping equipment unless the scaffold is specifically designed for this purpose.\n
    \n© Commonwealth of Australia 2014.</string>


    <string name="com_haz10"><b>Mixing Scaffold Components From Other Systems</b>\n
        Scaffolding from different manufacturers or suppliers, while sometimes looking compatible,
often has different dimensions and tolerances.\n

\nMixing incompatible scaffolding can reduce the structural integrity of a scaffold and could
lead to the collapse of the scaffold. It can also lead to increased wear on the scaffolding
and difficulties in disassembly which in turn may increase the risk of musculoskeletal injury
to workers.\n

    \nThe following controls can be used to prevent or minimise the risk of injury and scaffold
collapse due to the incorrect mixing of scaffolding:\n

\n<b>&#8226;  </b> Do not mix scaffolding from different manufacturers unless a competent person
e.g. an engineer has determined that:\n
\n<b>(a)  </b> the different scaffolding is of compatible size and strength
\n<b>(b)  </b> the different scaffolding has compatible deflection characteristics
\n<b>(c)  </b> the different fixing devices are compatible, and
\n<b>(d)  </b> mixing the different scaffolding does not lessen the strength, stability, rigidity or
suitability of the designed scaffold.\n

\n<b>&#8226;  </b> Do not mix scaffolding couplers and tubing of different outer diameters and strengths
unless designed specifically for the task by a competent person or the coupler
manufacturer has designed the couplers for this purpose. For example, do not mix
aluminium and steel scaffolding as steel clamps may cause aluminium tubing to be
crushed and reduce the strength of the tube.\n

\nBeam clamps or flange clamps should be provided with information about safe use
including tightening torque required. If no information is provided contact the supplier,
manufacturer or designer of the scaffold.

    \n© Commonwealth of Australia 2014.</string>

    <string name="com_haz11"><b>Powered Mobile Plant and Traffic</b>\n
        Powered mobile plant and vehicular traffic are hazards which can potentially affect worker
safety and the safe use and structural integrity of a scaffold.\n

\nControl measures to minimise the risks associated with moving plant and traffic include:\n
\n<b>&#8226;  </b> re-routing vehicles and mobile plant away from where the scaffold is located
e.g. by using traffic controllers to redirect traffic\n
\n<b>&#8226;  </b> using barricades, signs, posts, buffer rails, guards, concrete or timber kerbs to prevent
mobile plant and traffic from coming into contact with a scaffold, and\n
\n<b>&#8226;  </b> ensuring the scaffold does not have unnecessary protrusions e.g. over-length transoms,
putlogs, tie tubes or over-height standards.\n

    \n© Commonwealth of Australia 2014.</string>

    <string name="com_haz12"><b>Supporting Structures</b>\n
        You should consider the capability of a supporting structure such as a building to bear
the most adverse combination of loads possible when erecting and using the scaffold.
Get advice from a competent person before anchoring a scaffold to a building or erecting
scaffolds on verandas, suspended flooring systems, parapets and awnings.\n

\nPropping of the supporting structure may be required where the supporting structure
is not capable of bearing the most adverse combination of loads.

    \n© Commonwealth of Australia 2014.</string>

    <string name="com_haz13"><b>Unauthorised Access</b>\n
        A person with management or control of a scaffold at a workplace must prevent
unauthorised access to the scaffold while the scaffold is incomplete or unattended.
This applies to suspended, cantilevered, spur or hung scaffolds, as well as any scaffold
from which a person or thing could fall more than 4 metres.\n

\nEntry to scaffold areas should be restricted to those carrying out the scaffolding work
while the scaffold is being erected, altered, repaired or dismantled. Control measures,
for example barriers and warning signs should be used to prevent unauthorised access
when the scaffold is left unattended.\n

    \n© Commonwealth of Australia 2014.</string>

    <!--General Design-->

    <string name="design_principles"><b>Design Principles</b>\n

The design of the scaffold should take into account:\n
\n<b>•</b> the strength, stability and rigidity of the supporting structure
\n<b>•</b> the intended use and application of the scaffold
\n<b>•</b> the safety of persons engaged in the erection, alteration and dismantling of the scaffold
\n<b>•</b> the safety of persons using the scaffold; and
\n<b>•</b> the safety of persons in the vicinity of the scaffold.\n

    \n© Commonwealth of Australia 2014.</string>

    <string name="foundation1"><b>Foundations</b>\n

Scaffolding foundations must be able to carry and distribute all the weight of the scaffold, including any extra loads,
        for example, perimeter containment screens, placed on the scaffold.
Consideration should be given to the following when designing the foundation of the scaffolding.\n

\n<b>Ground Conditions</b>\n

        Water and nearby excavations may lead to soil subsidence and the collapse of scaffold. Any likely watercourse, such as a recently filled trench, which has the potential to create a wash out under the scaffold base, should be diverted away from the scaffold.
The principal contractor or PCBU should ensure ground conditions are stable and inform scaffold erectors of any factors which may affect ground stability, before the scaffold is erected.\n


   </string>

<string name="foundation2">\n<b>Loads</b>\n

Scaffolding needs to be designed for the most adverse combination of dead, live and environmental loads that can reasonably be expected during the period that the scaffold is in use.
The dead, live and environmental loads will need to be calculated during the design stage to ensure the supporting structure and the lower standards are capable of supporting the loads. The design of such scaffolds and ties must be approved by a competent person or an engineer.
Follow the specifications of the manufacturer, designer or supplier for the maximum loads of the scaffold.\n

\n<b>Environmental Loads</b>\n

Consider environmental loads, particularly the effects of wind and rain on the scaffold. For example, environmental loads imposed by wind and rain may be heightened if perimeter containment screens,
        shadecloth or signs are attached to the scaffold. Staggering the joints in standards may help control the risk of scaffold collapse from environmental loads.\n

    \n<b>Dead Loads</b>\n

    Dead loads refer to the self weight of the scaffold structure and components including any working, catch or access platforms, stairways, ladders, screens, sheeting, platform brackets, suspension ropes,
    secondary ropes, traversing ropes, tie assemblies, scaffolding hoists or electrical cables. Dead loads should be calculated in accordance with AS/NZS 1576.1 Scaffolding – General Requirements.\n

    \n<b>Live Loads</b>\n

    The live load includes:\n

\n<b>•</b> the weight of persons
\n<b>•</b> the weight of materials and debris
\n<b>•</b> the weight of tools and equipment; and
\n<b>•</b> the safety of persons using the scaffold; and
\n<b>•</b> impact forces.\n

    \nScaffolds should not be used to support formwork and plant, such as hoist towers and concrete pumping equipment,
    unless the scaffold is specifically designed for this purpose.
The live loads applied to a working platform should be in accordance with those specified in Table 1.\n

\n© Commonwealth of Australia 2014.
</string>

    <string name="soleboards1"><b>Supporting Structure</b>\n

   Consider the capability of the supporting structure to bear the most adverse combination of loads possible during the use of the scaffold.
        Obtain advice from an engineer before erecting scaffolds on verandas, suspended flooring systems, compacted soil, parapets and awnings.\n

\nPropping may be required where the supporting structure is not capable of bearing the most adverse combination of loads.\n

\n<b>Soleboards and baseplates</b>\n

Soleboards and baseplates should evenly distribute
the load from the scaffold to the supporting
surface to provide scaffold stability. A
soleboard distributes the load from a load-bearing
member to a supporting surface and is intended for
use underneath baseplates.\n

\nBoth soleboards and baseplates may be required for
use on less stable surfaces, for example soil, gravel,
or fill. The size of the soleboard will vary depending
on the supporting surface. They can be placed under
a single standard or multiple standards as in Figure
1. Where necessary a competent person should
determine the bearing capacity of the ground or
other supporting structure.\n

\nSoleboards and baseplates should be level.
Adjustable bases can be used on uneven surfaces
for modular scaffold systems to give a level base lift.
No part of the baseplate or adjustable base should
protrude over the side of the soleboard to ensure
the loads are carried evenly on the soleboard.\n

\nNeedles and spurs should be considered where
ground conditions are very unstable.\n

        \n<b>Stability</b>\n

Scaffold stability may be achieved by:\n

\n<b>•</b> tying the scaffold to a supporting structure
\n<b>•</b> guying to a supporting structure
\n<b>•</b> increasing the dead load by securely attaching counterweights near the base; and
\n<b>•</b> adding bays to increase the base dimension.\n

        \n© Commonwealth of Australia 2014.
    </string>

     <string name="tying1"><b>Tying and Anchoring</b>\n

        Tie methods and spacing should be in accordance with the manufacturer, designer
or supplier instructions. Consult the scaffold designer, manufacturer, supplier or an
engineer if it is not practical to position the ties in accordance with the instructions.\n

         \nControl measures for tying scaffold include:\n

\n<b>•</b> Using more ties if:\n
    \n<b>(a)</b> the scaffold is sheeted or netted due to increased wind loadings
    \n<b>(b)</b> it is used as a loading platform for materials or equipment, and
    \n<b>(c)</b> lifting appliances or rubbish chutes are attached.\n

\n<b>•</b> Regularly inspecting scaffold ties to check they are not modified or altered by
unauthorised people e.g. finishing trades who may loosen, relocate or remove ties
to gain access to walls and openings.\n
\n<b>•</b> Not attaching extra loads to the scaffold e.g. signs and perimeter containment screens,
without first consulting a competent person like the scaffold design engineer or the
supplier.\n
\n<b>•</b> Using cast-in anchors or through bolts that pass through a wall in preference to
expansion or chemical anchors for securing scaffold ties because of possible failure
due to faulty tensioning or chemical adhesion.\n
\n<b>•</b> Deformation-controlled anchors, thread cutting anchors and insert type anchors should
not be used.\n
\n<b>•</b> Drill-in expansion anchors should be limited to the load (torque) controlled type—the
working load limit (WLL) should be limited to 65 percent of the ‘first slip load’ stated
in the information provided by the supplier.\n
\n<b>•</b> All drill-in expansion anchors should be installed using a torque wrench set to the
required torque, unless the anchor has an in-built torque indicator. Documented
verification should be kept on site stating:\n
    \n<b>(a)</b> the anchor setting torque
    \n<b>(b)</b> install date, and
    \n<b>(c)</b> location and name of the competent person installing the anchors.\n

\n<b>•</b> Where chemical anchors are used, all anchors should be tested and proof loaded to the
working load multiplied by a factor of 1.25.\n
\n<b>•</b> All insert anchors including expansion and chemical anchors should have a safety factor
of 3 to 1 on their failure load. If any anchors fail the remaining anchors on the same level
should be tested.\n
\n<b>•</b> Ties should not obstruct access along the working and access platforms.\n
\n<b>•</b> Ties should interconnect with both the inner and outer scaffold standards unless
otherwise specified by an engineer to increase the rigidity of the scaffold.\n
\n<b>•</b> Ties from scaffold to structure should be designed to be non-pivoting and fully secured
to ensure they cannot be loosened.\n
         \n© Commonwealth of Australia 2014.

</string>

    <string name="working_platform1"><b>Working Platforms</b>\n

   Working platforms, except suspended scaffolds, should have duty classifications and
dimensions complying with the manufacturer’s information on loadings. Scaffold working
platforms are generally rated as light, medium or heavy duty:\n

\n<b>• Light Duty</b> – up to 225 kg per platform per bay including a concentrated load of
120 kg. Platforms should be at least two traditional scaffold planks wide—approximately
450 mm. Use examples include painting, electrical work, many carpentry tasks and
other light tasks.\n

\n<b>• Medium Duty</b> – up to 450 kg per platform per bay including a concentrated load of
150 kg. Platforms should be at least four traditional scaffold planks wide—approximately
900 mm. Use examples include general trades work like tiling and light steel framing.\n

\n<b>• Heavy Duty</b> – up to 675 kg per platform per bay including a concentrated load of
200 kg. Platforms should be at least 1000 mm wide. This duty scaffold is needed for
concrete block laying, bricklaying, concreting, demolition work and most other tasks
involving heavy loads or heavy impact forces.\n

\n<b>• Special Duty</b> – has a designated allowable load as designed.\n

\nEach scaffold should be designed to carry the required number of working platforms and
to support the dead and live loads. Where tools or materials are to be used or stored on
working platforms, an unobstructed access width of at least 450 mm should be maintained.
Scaffold planks on working platforms should:\n

\n<b>•</b> have a slip-resistant surface\n
\n<b>•</b> not be cracked or split\n
\n<b>•</b> be of uniform thickness\n
\n<b>•</b> be secure—so it cannot be kicked off or susceptible to uplift or displacement during
normal use\n
\n<b>•</b> be positioned so no single gap between planks exceeds 10 mm, and\n
\n<b>•</b> not be lapped on straight runs of modular and tube and coupler scaffolding but may
be lapped on hanging bracket scaffolds where butting of planks at a pair of brackets
cannot be achieved.\n

\nLapped scaffold planks may sometimes be used to cover gaps around corners of scaffold.
These planks should be safely secured. In some circumstances they may not need to be
secured provided the following are met:\n

\n<b>•</b> timber is lapped over metal planks\n
\n<b>•</b> planks are 1.2 metres long or greater\n
\n<b>•</b> plank overlap—past the edge of the plank underneath—is 300 mm or greater, and\n
\n<b>•</b> standards prevent planks from moving sideways on the scaffold.\n

\nIn these cases wind forces should be considered and if wind is a potential hazard then the
lapping planks should be secured.
If using plywood sheets to cover gaps between scaffold bays the plywood sheets should
be:\n

\n<b>•</b>a minimum of 17 mm thick\n
\n<b>•</b> only used to cover gaps less than 500 mm wide unless approved by an engineer, and\n
        \n<b>•</b>secured.\n

\nMetal planks lapped on other metal planks should be secured using fixings, for example
metal strapping. Tie wire or another system not structurally rated should not be used to
secure planks on hop-up brackets.\n

        \nMore generally:\n

\n<b>•</b> Planks should be secured.\n
\n<b>•</b> Each hop-up bracket should be provided with tie bars unless constructed with scaffold
planks locked into position to stop brackets from spreading apart or causing planks to
dislodge unless otherwise specified by the scaffold designer.\n
\n<b>•</b> The overhang of planks which are supported by putlogs should be greater than 150 mm
but less than 250 mm—otherwise uplift might occur.\n
\n<b>•</b> Avoid nailing or screwing laminated planks into position unless otherwise specified by
the manufacturer. Moisture penetrating the planks can cause damage and may not be
easily detected.\n

        \n© Commonwealth of Australia 2014.

</string>

    <string name="fall_arrest"><b>Fall Arrest Platform</b>\n
A fall arresting platform can be used as a control measure to arrest a person’s fall during work at height.\n

        \nIf the slope of the surface where work is being done is:\n
\n<b>(a)</b> not over 26º – then install the platform no more than 1 metre lower than the surface; or\n
\n<b>(b)</b> over 26º – then install the platform no more than 300 mm lower than the surface.\n

        \nThe fall arresting platform must:\n

        \n<b>(a)</b> be unobstructed and at least 675 mm wide for the length of the platform;\n

        \n<b>(b)</b> be able to withstand the impact of a fall onto it; and\n

        \n<b>(c)</b> have edge protection erected:\n

        \n<b>i.</b>along the outer edge of the length of the platform; and\n

        \n<b>ii.</b> along the edges of each end of the fall arresting platform.\n

    \nIf the internal gap (the gap between the inner edge of the length of the platform and the face of the building or structure immediately beside the platform) exceeds 225 mm,
        then implement a control measure to control the risk of a fall.\n

        \n© Commonwealth of Australia 2014.

    </string>

    <string name="edge_protection">

        <b>Edge Protection</b>\n

        Edge protection may be used as a control measure to prevent the risk of death or injury from a fall during work at height.\n

        \nObtain written approval from an engineer before installing edge protection on a scaffold system which was not originally designed,
        supplied or manufactured with edge protection. Approval should include specifications on how to install and maintain edge protection.\n

        \n© Commonwealth of Australia 2014.

    </string>

    <string name="entry_egress">

        <b> Access and Egress</b>\n

        Workers must be provided with safe access to and egress from scaffold during the erection, use and dismantling of scaffolding.
        Common means of access and egress include:\n

\n<b>•</b> temporary stairs or portable ladder access systems installed at the start of erection, progressed with the scaffold, and used by the scaffolder
        whenever possible\n
\n<b>•</b> permanently installed platforms or ramp;\n
\n<b>•</b> personnel hoists (non-mechanical forms of egress, such as a ladder or stair tower should be provided in case of emergency); and\n
\n<b>•</b> using the existing floor level of a building, provided such access is safe.
        Scaffolders should not climb standards externally.\n

        \n<b>Ladders</b>\n

\nThe following are additional safe work practices which should be followed when working on ladders:\n

\n<b>•</b> Ladders may be used where access to the working platform is needed by only a few persons, and where tools and equipment can
        be delivered separately to the working platform (for example, by materials hoist, crane or a rope and gin wheel).\n
\n<b>•</b> Ladders should be within a separate ladder access bay of the scaffold, wherever space permits.\n
\n<b>•</b> If the access bay is part of the working platform, a trap door is to be provided. Strict controls are to be implemented to
        ensure the trap door remains closed while working from the platform.\n
\n<b>•</b> Ladders should be set up on a firm, level surface and not used on scaffold bays to gain extra height.\n

        \n© Commonwealth of Australia 2014.

    </string>

    <string name="contain_screen1"><b>Perimeter Containment Screening</b>\n

Perimeter containment screening is used to protect persons from falling objects.
Perimeter containment screens must be made of mesh, timber, plywood, metal sheeting or other material suitable for the purpose.\n

    </string>

    <string name="contain_screen2"><b>Perimeter Containment Screening</b>\n

    Perimeter containment screens must be located inside the standards on working platforms.\n

    \nThe prescribed lining2 must be attached to the inside of the mesh.
        The prescribed lining can be attached using non-structural locating product
        which keeps the lining in place while minimising damage to the lining.\n

    \nThe framework supporting a screen must be able to bear the load of the screen.
    Each of the following gaps must be not over 25 mm:\n
    \n<b>(a)</b> the gap, measured horizontally, between screens immediately beside each other\n
    \n<b>(b)</b> the gap, measured vertically, between a screen and another screen immediately above it; and\n
    \n<b>(c)</b> the gap, measured vertically and horizontally, between a screen and the framework supporting it.
Containment sheeting should be installed no higher than the upper most tie, unless certified otherwise by an engineer..\n

        \nWhere work is carried out close to pedestrian or vehicular access,
        scaffolds that are sheeted down to hoarding level can minimise both the risk to the public and the area lost to public access.\n

        \n© Commonwealth of Australia 2014.

    </string>

    <string name="basic"><b>Basic Scaffolding Licence</b>\n
        Required for scaffolding work involving:\n
\n<b>•</b> modular or prefabricated scaffolds\n
\n<b>•</b> cantilevered materials hoists with a maximum working load of 500 kilograms\n
\n<b>•</b> ropes\n
\n<b>•</b> gin wheels\n
\n<b>•</b> fall arrest systems including safety nets and static lines, and\n
\n<b>•</b> bracket scaffolds (tank and formwork.\n

        \n<b>Basic Scaffolder Knowledge</b>

        \n<b>•</b> The height above the maximum nut extension above the spindle of an adjustable baseplate should be 150mm.\n

        \n<b>•</b> The maximum extension on an adjustable baseplate is 600mm.\n

        \n<b>•</b> The minimum size of a square baseplate is 150mm x 150mm (or 225cm2).\n

        \n<b>•</b> The minimum outside diameter of a common scaffold tube (to the nearest mm)is 48mm\n

        \n<b>•</b> The minimum wall thickness of a common steel scaffold tube is 4mm\n

        \n<b>•</b> The minimum wall thickness of a common heavy duty aluminium scaffold tube is 4.45mm (or 4.4mm or 4.5mm).\n

        \n<b>•</b> The minimum width of a scaffold plank is 220mm (or 225mm).\n

        \n<b>•</b> The minimum thickness of a hardwood solid timber scaffold plank is 32mm.\n

        \n<b>•</b> The minimum thickness of an oregon solid timber scaffold plank 38mm.\n

        \n<b>•</b> The minimum diameter of fibre rope you would use for a handline is 12mm.\n

        \n<b>•</b> The minimum diameter of fibre rope you would use for a gin wheel is 16mm.\n

        \n<b>•</b> The maximum load you would lift with a gin wheel is 50kg.\n

        \n<b>•</b> The distance you would fix a gin wheel along an unbraced cantilevered scaffold tube would be 600mm.\n

        \n<b>•</b> The maximum load in each bay of a medium duty working platform is 450kg (or 4.4kN).\n

        \n<b>•</b> The maximum load in each bay of a heavy duty working platform is 675kg (or 6.6kN).\n

        \n<b>•</b> The maximum load would you place on a right angle coupler is 630kg (or 630kgf or 6.25kN).\n

        \n<b>•</b> The maximum load would you place an adjustable baseplate is 3030kg (or 30kN, or 3030kgf. 3000kg or 3 t are acceptable approximations).\n

        \n<b>•</b> The maximum allowable load on a chain is One sixth of the breaking load (or breaking strain or breaking force).\n

        \n<b>•</b> The maximum allowable load on a flexible steel wire rope is One sixth of the breaking load (or breaking strain or breaking force) .\n

        \n<b>•</b> When a scaffold is built on soil, you would place a soleboard under the baseplates to distribute the load.\n

        \n<b>•</b> The minimum width of timber you would use as a soleplate is 220mm (or 225mm, or the width of a scaffold plank).\n

        \n<b>•</b> No gaps allowed between the planks of a working platform.\n

        \n<b>•</b> Platform planks can be lapped on the returns of a scaffold.\n

        \n<b>•</b> The minimum width of a light duty working platform is 450mm (or 2 planks).\n

        \n<b>•</b> The minimum width of a medium duty working platform is 900mm (or 4 planks).\n

        \n<b>•</b> The minimum width of a heavy duty working platform is 1000m (or 5 planks).\n

        \n<b>•</b> The minimum width of clear access along a working platform for persons with hand tools only is 450mm (or 2 planks).

        \n<b>•</b> The minimum width of a clear access along a working platform for persons and materials is 675mm (or 3 planks).\n

        \n<b>•</b> Planks with different thicknesses cannot be used to deck out a working platform.\n

        \n<b>•</b> Edge protection is needed when working on platforms more than 2m in height (or when a person can fall more than 2m).\n

        \n<b>•</b> A toeboard must extend 150mm above the working platform.\n

        \n<b>•</b> On a working platform a guardrail should not be fixed less than 900mm and no greater than 1100mm.\n

        \n<b>•</b> The maximum gap allowed between an unprotected platform edge and the working face is less than 225mm.\n

        \n<b>•</b> There are 3 types of ladders that cannot be used to access a scaffold, Domestic grade ladders, Extension ladders and step ladders.\n

        \n<b>•</b> The maximum height allowed between ladder landings is 6m (3 lifts).\n

        \n<b>•</b> The minimum height a access ladder must extend above the landing is 900mm or 1m.\n

        \n<b>•</b> Mobile scaffolds need wheel locks.\n

        \n<b>•</b> Mobile Scaffolds cannot have pneumatic tyres.\n

        \n<b>•</b> Mobile scaffolds require plan bracing to stop the scaffold from twisting when moved.\n

        \n<b>•</b> The minimum platform width when platform brackets (hop ups) are fixed between lifts is 450mm or 2 planks.\n

        \n<b>•</b> The maximum spacing between tank brackets supporting 50mm thick timber is 2m.\n

        \n<b>•</b> The maximum spacing between tank brackets supporting 63mmmm thick timber is 2.5m.\n

        \n<b>•</b> Timbers are to be lashed down to stop the movement of timbers on a platform.\n

        \n<b>•</b> A sheeted scaffold must be check by an engineer.\n

        \n<b>•</b> Never mix  scaffold components.\n

        \n<b>•</b> The maximum horizontal tie spacing used on a modular scaffold is 3 bays or 6 bays with plan bracing.\n

        \n<b>•</b> The maximum vertical tie spacing you would use on a modular scaffold is 4m (2 lifts), or 8m with ledger bracing (4 lifts with ledger bracing).\n

        \n<b>•</b> 3 unbraced panels are allowed between the longitudinally braced panels of the modular scaffold.\n

        \n<b>•</b> A free standing steel framed scaffold can be no higher than three times the least base width.\n

        \n<b>•</b> A tower frame scaffold access ladder should be fitted internally.\n

        \n<b>•</b> The maximum mesh size for a safety net is 100mm.\n

        \n<b>•</b> The maximum gap between the edge of the safety net and the building or structure is 200mm.

        \n<b>•</b> The two maximum fall distances found on the label of the safety net is 1m and 6m.\n

        \n<b>•</b> The minimum and maximum initial sag of a safety net is 1/4 and 1/5 of the shortest side.\n

        \n<b>•</b> The minimum clearance below a safety net is 2/3 of the shortest side lendth or 2m, which ever is greatest.

        \n<b>•</b> The maximum spacing between ties along the border chord of a safety net is 750mm.\n

        \n<b>•</b> The minimum overrun distance between the hoist rope attachment and the head sheave on a cantilevered platform hoist is 1.5m.\n

        \n<b>•</b> The minimum and maximum horizontal clearance between the moving platform of a cantilevered hoist and any landing is 25mm and 100mm.\n

        \n<b>•</b> The minimum height of a landing gate for a cantilevered platform hoist is 1.8m.\n

        \n<b>•</b> The maximum distance you would use between lateral braces of a cantilevered platform hoist is 6m.\n

        \n<b>•</b> The height you would free stand a tower of a cantilevered platform hoist above its last tie is 3m.\n

        \n© Commonwealth of Australia 2014.

    </string>

    <string name="intermediate"><b>Intermediate Scaffolding Licence</b>\n

        Required for scaffolding work involving:\n

\n<b>•</b> cantilevered crane loading platforms\n
\n<b>•</b> cantilevered scaffolds\n
\n<b>•</b> spur scaffolds\n
\n<b>•</b> barrow ramps and sloping platforms\n
\n<b>•</b> scaffolding associated with perimeter safety screens and shutters\n
\n<b>•</b> mast climbing work platforms, and\n
\n<b>•</b> tube and coupler scaffolds including tube and coupler covered ways and gantries.\n

        \n<b>Intermediate Scaffolder Knowledge</b>

        \n<b>•</b> A intermediate scaffolder cannot build a personnel and materials hoist.\n

        \n<b>•</b> A intermediate scaffolder can install a cantilevered crane loading platform.\n

        \n<b>•</b> A intermediate scaffolder is not allowed to build a hung scaffold.\n

        \n<b>•</b> A intermediate scaffolder is allowed to build a barrow ramp.\n

        \n<b>•</b> A intermediate scaffolder can build a single pole tube and coupler scaffold.\n

        \n<b>•</b>  A intermediate scaffolder can build a tube and coupler covered way or gantry.\n

        \n<b>•</b>  A intermediate scaffolder can build a mast climber.\n

        \n<b>•</b>  A intermediate scaffolder can build a cantilevered or spurred scaffold.\n

        \n<b>•</b> The maximum height for a tube and coupler scaffold is 45m.\n

        \n<b>•</b> The maximum bay with for a light duty independent scaffold is 2.4m or 2 planks.\n

        \n<b>•</b> The minimum bay width for a medium duty independent scaffold is 950mm or 4 planks.\n

        \n<b>•</b> The maximum bay width for a heavy duty independent scaffold is 1.275m or 5 plants.\n

        \n<b>•</b> The maximum bay length for a light duty independent scaffold is 3m.\n

        \n<b>•</b> or a medium duty independent scaffold is 2.4m.\n

        \n<b>•</b> The maximum bay length for a single pole scaffold is 1.8m\n

        \n<b>•</b> The maximum lift height for a normal independent scaffold is 2m.\n

        \n<b>•</b> A ledger can be joined 300mm from the standard.\n

        \n<b>•</b> A standard can be joined 300mm from a ledger.\n

        \n<b>•</b>\n19. When putlogs are cantilevered to support extra planks, the minimum bay width is 950mm or 4 planks.\n

        \n<b>•</b> two 250mm planks can be supported by the cantilevered portion of putlogs.\n

        \n<b>•</b> 4 full length working platforms can be carried on a 15m high steel tube scaffold.\n

        \n<b>•</b> 2 full length working platform can be carried on a 45m high steel tube scaffold.\n

        \n<b>•</b> 1 full length working platform can be carried on a 45m high aluminium tube scaffold.\n

        \n<b>•</b> The first level of ties on a single pole scaffold should be on the first lift.\n

        \n<b>•</b> The maximum heigh of a mobile scaffold is 3 times its least base width.\n

        \n<b>•</b> The maximum angle from the vertical for spurs in an access opening is 45 degrees.\n

        \n<b>•</b> The maximum height for puncheons in an access opening is 30m.\n

        \n<b>•</b> Where double standards ore used, the maximum first lift height is 3m.\n

        \n<b>•</b> The maximum angle for sloping putlogs on a cantilevered catch platform is 60 degrees or 30 degress th the horizontal.\n

        \n<b>•</b> The maximum spacing between intermediate sloping putlogs on a cantilevered catch platform is 600mm.\n

        \n<b>•</b> The maximum width of a cantilevered catch platform is 1.125m or 5 planks.\n

        \n<b>•</b> The first lift on a mobile scaffold is as close to the castors as possible.\n

        \n<b>•</b> The maximum allowable slope of a working platform is 7 degreses or 1 in 8.\n

        \n<b>•</b> The cleats on a platform of a barrow ramp should be fixed 450mm apart.\n

        \n<b>•</b> The size of the gap you would leave for a wheel of a barrow in a barrow ramp cleat is 100mm\n

        \n<b>•</b> A single set of spurs would support 5 lifts.\n

        \n<b>•</b> The minimum width of a steel beam you would use aas a needle for a cantilever scaffold is 75mm\n

        \n<b>•</b> A cantilever scaffold needle should be inboard 3 times the outboard or 3 quarters, or 75%.\n

        \n<b>•</b> To stop the nuts from loosening on the anchorage bolts of a cantilever scaffold needle use lock nuts.\n

        \n<b>•</b> U-Head baseplates would be used to fix the standards of a cantilever scaffold to the needles.\n

        \n<b>•</b> You would place the first lift of ledgers and transoms on a cantilever scaffold as close to the needles as possible.\n

        \n<b>•</b> The minimum diameter of bolts you would use to anchor the inboard end of a cantilever scaffold needle is 15mm\n

        \n<b>•</b> You would not use drilled in anchors ti fix the inboard end of a cantilever scaffold needle.\n

        \n<b>•</b> When a spur is in compression, The maximum length between node points is 2m.\n

        \n<b>•</b> To fix a spur to a scaffold framework you would use a right angle coupler.\n

        \n<b>•</b> The maximum angle from the vertical at which you would fix a spur is 45 degrees.\n

        \n© Commonwealth of Australia 2014.

    </string>

    <string name="advanced">
     <b>Advanced Scaffolding Licence</b>\n

    Required for scaffolding work involving:\n

    \n<b>•</b> cantilevered hoists\n
    \n<b>•</b> hung scaffolds including scaffolds hung from tubes, wire ropes or chains, and\n
    \n<b>•</b> suspended scaffolds.\n

     \n<b>Advance Scaffolder Knowledge</b>

    \n<b>•</b> You would not use open ended hook rods to build a hung scaffold.\n

    \n<b>•</b> The minimum diameter of flexible steel wire rope you would use to support a hung scaffold is 11mm.\n

    \n<b>•</b> A grade (M) chain would support a Lesser load than a grade (T) chain.\n

    \n<b>•</b> The minim working load limit for beam clamps, trolleys and shackles used to support a hung scaffold is 500kg\n

    \n<b>•</b> To protect a flexible steel wire rope from damage when it is fixed around the sharp edges of a beam use beam chaffer\'s\n

    \n<b>•</b> When a ledger is supported in the eye of a sling, you would stop it from sliding by fixing a coupler on each side.\n

    \n<b>•</b> Mouse shackle pins to stop them unwinding.\n

    \n<b>•</b> Speed threads are unsuitable for fixing hung standards.\n

    \n<b>•</b> You would not extend the length of a hung standard by fixing scaffold tubes with end to end couplers.\n

    \n<b>•</b> The minimum rated working load for a trolley used to support a suspension rope is 500kg.\n

    \n<b>•</b> You would fix a cradle\'s working load limit sign to the inside of the cradle.\n

    \n<b>•</b> The minimum cradle width for a double rope suspended scaffold is 900mm.\n

    \n<b>•</b> The maximum cradle width for a double rope suspended scaffold is 1.7m.\n

    \n<b>•</b> The minimum width of a swing stage cradle is 450mm.\n

    \n<b>•</b> The maximum width of a swing stage cradle is 900mm.\n

    \n<b>•</b> The minimum width of a work cage is 750mm.\n

    \n<b>•</b> The maximum width of a work cage is 1.5m.\n

    \n<b>•</b> The minimum height of a stabilising sheave above the platform of a wrk cage is 2m.\n

    \n<b>•</b> You would not fix the inboard end of a needle with friction anchors.\n

    \n<b>•</b> You cannot use bags of sand as a counterweight for a needle.\n

    \n<b>•</b> You would not use counterweights to fix a needle which supports two suspension ropes.\n

    \n<b>•</b> The maximum rop tension allowed on a shackle use to support a suspension rop is 80 percent or the rated working load or 80 percent of SWL.\n

    \n<b>•</b> The maximum rop tension allowed on a choked sling used to support a suspension rope is 40 percent of rated working load or 40 percent of SWL.\n

    \n<b>•</b> Where two trolleys are used to support a swing stage, To stop them from spreading you would connect them with a spacer tie (or speader bar).\n

    \n<b>•</b> When a drum type scaffolding hoist is at its lowest point, 3 full turns of rope should remain on the drum.\n

    \n<b>•</b> With a fully loaded drum type scaffolding hoist, The drum flange should extend 2 rope diameters beyond the build up of rope.\n

    \n<b>•</b> When a climber type scaffolding hoist is at its lowest point, The minimum length of spare rope is 1m.\n

    \n<b>•</b> You would not use bulldog grips to secure a suspension rope.\n

    \n<b>•</b> A double rope suspended scaffold does not need a protective device for each scaffolding hoist.\n

    \n<b>•</b> An electronically powered scaffolding hoist must be fitted with a load limiting device\n

        \n© Commonwealth of Australia 2014.



    </string>

    <string name="tower_mobile1">

        \n<b>Tower and Mobile Scaffolds</b>\n

A tower scaffold is an independent scaffold
consisting of four vertical standards
connected longitudinally and transversely
or two frames in plan connected
transversely to create a scaffold of one bay.
It may also have an extra, short stabiliser
bay or outriggers to increase stability.\n

\nA mobile scaffold is a tower scaffold
mounted on wheels.\n

    </string>


     <string name="tower_mobile2">

       Manufacturers and suppliers must provide
information about how to use and erect
mobile scaffolds safely. If a scaffold is to
be altered contact the manufacturer or
supplier for guidance. Prefabricated mobile
scaffolds should be erected in accordance
with manufacturer’s specifications.\n

\n<b>When do I need a high
risk work licence?</b>\n

A licensed scaffolder is required
for the erection, alteration or dismantling of
a tower or mobile scaffold where there is a
risk that a person or object could fall more
than 4 metres from the platform or the
structure.
This means that if a scaffold that is less than
4 metres in height is located adjacent to, for
example an excavation, a licensed scaffolder
may still be required.

    </string>

     <string name="tower_mobile3">

Often tower and mobile scaffolds will not
require a licensed scaffolder to erect or
dismantle them as there is no risk of a fall
greater than 4 metres. However, the work
should still be carried out by a competent
person.\n

\n<b>Control Measures</b>\n

The following control measures should be
considered for tower and mobile scaffolds:\n

\n<b>•</b> Construct a tower scaffold with
modular, frame or tube and coupler
scaffolding.\n

\n<b>•</b> Locate a scaffold on firm level ground
with the feet or wheels properly
supported. Do not use loose bricks or
building blocks to take the weight of
the scaffold. Where adjustable wheels
are used, the slope of the surface
should not exceed 5 degrees.\n

\n<b>•</b> The height of the scaffold—from the
bottom of the scaffold to the platform
surface—should be no greater than the
multiple of the minimum base dimension
as specified in the manufacturer, supplier
or designer information.\n

\n<b>•</b> Reduce the height to base ratios or
provide extra support if the scaffold
will be:\n

\n<b>(a)</b> sheeted or likely to be exposed
to strong winds
\n<b>(b)</b> loaded with heavy equipment
or materials
\n<b>(c)</b> used to hoist heavy materials
or support rubbish chutes, and
\n<b>(d)</b> used for operations involving heavy
or awkward equipment e.g. grit
blasting or water-jetting.\n

\n<b>•</b> Use a secure internal ladder with a
protected opening e.g. a hinged trap
door for entry and exit to and from
the scaffold.\n

\n<b>•</b> The internal ladder should be free
of the supporting surface.\n

\n<b>•</b> Select the correct size and capacity
wheels to support the total mass of
the dead and live loads of the scaffold.\n

\n<b>•</b> Use wheels that have the working
load limit (WLL) clearly marked.\n

\n<b>•</b> Wheels should be locked before
erection continues.\n

\n<b>•</b> Wheels with adjustable legs should be
used and adjusted to keep the platform
level when the supporting structure is
at uneven or different heights.\n

\n<b>•</b> Include plan bracing at the base of
mobile scaffolds to provide greater
stability.\n

\n<b>•</b> Install guardrails, mid-rails and
toeboards on working platforms.

         \n<b>•</b> Keep wheel brakes locked at all times
unless moving the scaffold.\n

\nWork should not be done from tower or
mobile scaffolds located on balconies or
raised areas unless the scaffold is stable
and secure or fixed to the structure to
prevent movement.\n

\n<b>Moving a scaffold</b>\n

Before moving or relocating
a scaffold check:\n

\n<b>•</b>  there are no people or materials on
the scaffold\n

\n<b>•</b>  there are no overhead electric lines
or other overhead obstructions in the
line of travel\n

\n<b>•</b>  the ground is firm, level and there are
no obstructions—contact with a small
obstruction can cause a mobile scaffold
to overturn, and\n

\n<b>•</b>  that electrical equipment and leads
cannot become tangled with the
scaffold.\n

\nNever move the scaffold in windy
conditions.\n

\nScaffolds with components that are not
permanently fixed or which are not rated
for lifting should only be moved in frames
designed to lift individual components
e.g. stillage’s.\n

\nIf lifting a scaffold by crane, prepare a lifting
plan outlining safe lifting points and how
loose components like base jacks should
be secured. Sling the scaffold at the point
most likely to maintain stability and prevent
dislodgment of scaffolding components.\n

\nThe load should be slung by a licensed
dogger or rigger and manoeuvred in a
way that ensures the load remains stable.\n

\nA crane should not be used to lift
aluminium mobile scaffolds because
the scaffolding components may fail.\n

         \n© Commonwealth of Australia 2014.

    </string>

    <string name="birdcage">
        <b>Birdcage scaffold</b>\n

A birdcage scaffold is an independent scaffold consisting of more than two rows of
standards in both directions connected by ledgers and transoms (see Figure below). It is mainly
used for work carried out on a single level, for example ceilings. You should refer to the
designer’s or manufacturer’s specifications when erecting and dismantling birdcage
scaffolds made from modular scaffolding.\n

\nThe following risk control measures
should be implemented for birdcage
scaffolds made from tube and coupler
scaffolding:\n

\n<b>•</b> Only use birdcage scaffold to
support formwork if it has been
specifically designed for this
purpose.\n

\n<b>•</b> Provide longitudinal bracing or a
tied face at every third longitudinal
row of standards.\n

\n<b>•</b> Brace the outside row of standards
on each face and each third row
internally with longitudinal bracing.\n

\n<b>•</b> Provide transverse bracing at every
fourth bay on the ends of the
scaffold.\n

\n<b>•</b> Consider using elevating work
platforms to assist with erecting or
dismantling birdcage scaffolds.\n

\nA fall arrest system is generally not a suitable risk control measure for the erection or
dismantling of perimeter and birdcage scaffolds. You should refer to the General guide for
scaffolds and scaffolding work for further information on fall arrest systems.

        \n© Commonwealth of Australia 2014.

    </string>

    <string name="tube_coupler">

        <b>Tube and coupler scaffolding</b>\n

Tube and coupler scaffolds are built from tubing (tube) and joining or fixing components
(couplers) fixed together, to form a required scaffold design. They are frequently used
on structures with unusual design, shape or function. The versatility of tube and coupler
scaffolds means they can be assembled in a wide variety of different configurations. This
also means erecting tube and coupler scaffolds can be complex when compared to
prefabricated scaffolds.\n

\nThe diameter and strength of the tube and components being used to form a tube and
coupler scaffold will determine the load it can carry. For a scaffold incorporating plain steel
tube, the analysis and design should consider the most adverse combination of tubes by wall
thickness, strength of the tube material or both.\n

\nSteel tubes and aluminium tubes should not be mixed in one scaffold.\n

\nTubes of different wall thicknesses should not be interconnected by spigots or internaltype
end-to-end couplers unless extra measures are taken to positively secure the joint. For
example, fix a short tube with swivel couplers over and parallel to the joint (splicing) or fix a
bridle with right-angle couplers to the adjacent members.\n

\nMetal tube and coupler components should be regularly inspected for damage and particular
attention given to crushing, deformation, cracks, corrosion and splitting.\n

        \n© Commonwealth of Australia 2014.

    </string>

    <string name="hung">

       <b>Hung Scaffold</b>\n

A hung or hanging scaffold is an independent scaffold that hangs from another structure but
is not capable of being raised or lowered when in use.\n

    \nThe following control measures should be implemented for a hung scaffold:\n

    \n<b>•</b> The hung scaffold should be designed by a competent person and verification obtained
    that the structure that is to support the hung scaffold is capable of bearing the design
    load.\n

    \n<b>•</b> The scaffolding plan should include information about the position of the check couplers.\n

    \n<b>•</b> If a cantilevered suspension rig is to be used, information should be included on how the
    rig is to be constructed and secured.\n

    \n<b>•</b> Standards on a hung scaffold should be tension spliced or bolted with rated spigot
    connection as per the manufacturer’s specifications.\n

    \n<b>•</b> Each vertical hanging tube should be
    provided with check couplers at the
    suspension points and underneath
    the platform or according to the
    manufacturer’s specifications.\n

        \n© Commonwealth of Australia 2014.

    </string>

     <string name="single_pole">

       <b>Single Pole Scaffold</b>\n

A single pole scaffold consists of a single
row of standards connected by ledgers
(see Figure below). Putlogs are fixed to the
ledgers and built into the wall of the
building or structure.\n

\nA single pole scaffold is dependent
upon the structure against which it is
placed for support. It is important that
no components of this type of scaffold
are removed until the scaffold is being
dismantled.\n

         \n© Commonwealth of Australia 2014.

    </string>

    <string name="swing_stage">

        <b>Suspended Scaffolds</b>\n

A suspended scaffold incorporates a suspended platform capable of being raised or lowered
when in use. Other terms often used are ‘suspended cradle’ and ‘swing-stage’ scaffold. They
are typically prefabricated modular units (see Figure 1) or permanently fabricated units
although they can be assembled from scaffolding.\n

        \n© Commonwealth of Australia 2014.

    </string>

     <string name="swing_stage2">

A suspended scaffold must be designed by a competent person and must be erected by a
person holding an advanced scaffolding or advanced rigging high risk work licence. Operators
do not require a licence but must be competent.\n

\nDesigner or manufacturer instructions should be followed when installing, erecting and
operating a suspended scaffold.\n

         \nRisk control measures that should be implemented for
a suspended scaffold include:\n

\n<b>•</b> providing safe entry to and exit from the cradle\n

\n<b>•</b> consulting with and providing specific training and instruction for workers on the correct
procedures for using and working on suspended scaffolds including instructions on safety
features like:\n

\n<b>(a)</b> the emergency stop, load limiting device and rope lock device
\n<b>(b)</b> rescue or emergency evacuation devices or equipment
\n<b>(c)</b> raising and lowering operations particularly in the event of an emergency
e.g. a power failure\n

\n<b>•</b> developing and implementing a rescue and retrieval procedure before starting work
including all necessary equipment, and\n

\n<b>•</b> inspecting components for damage, wear and cracks before use and at pre-determined
intervals. Non-destructive testing for cracks in high stress areas e.g. dye penetration
testing may be needed to identify cracks not easily visible.\n

\n<b>Design</b>\n

The suspension rig should be designed and documented by a competent person, for example
a person who holds a tertiary qualification in a relevant engineering discipline.\n

\nEvery area of design for a suspended scaffold system should receive a formal sign-off from
a competent person. The formal sign-off for the suspended scaffold system should include
the needle suspension system, cradle and hoist. Different parties may certify different
components.\n

For further information such as:
         \n<b>•</b>Installation
         \n<b>•</b>Supply
         \n<b>•</b>Setup\n

\n refer to <i>Guide to Suspended (Swing Stage) Scaffolds</i> or click the button below.\n

         \n© Commonwealth of Australia 2014.

    </string>

<string name="demolition"><b>Scaffolds for Demolition work</b>\n

At a minimum, heavy or special duty (see below) scaffold should be used during demolition
work to contain dislodged materials or to provide a safe working platform and edge
protection for workers.\n

\nFactors which affect the stability of a scaffold for demolition work include:\n

\n<b>•</b> the load imposed by demolished material dislodged onto the scaffold\n
\n<b>•</b> wind forces acting on containment sheeting on the scaffold face\n
\n<b>•</b> water retention in containment sheeting by capillary attraction\n
\n<b>•</b> progressive removal of building elements affecting the lateral stability of the upper
portion of the scaffold, and\n
\n<b>•</b> progressive removal of ties and dismantling of the scaffold.\n

    \nThe following risk control measures should be implemented when using scaffolds for
demolition work:\n

\n<b>•</b> The vertical spacing of scaffold ties may have to be reduced to facilitate the demolition
cycle.\n
\n<b>•</b> Containment sheeting on the internal face of the scaffold should be installed to deflect
material into the building. This reduces the potential for overloading the scaffold.\n
\n<b>•</b> Ensure the scaffold is dismantled progressively and in line with the demolition work.\n
\n<b>•</b> Scaffold planks should be secured to prevent dislodgement from falling debris.\n
\n<b>•</b> The scaffold should be maintained and inspected regularly.\n

    \n© Commonwealth of Australia 2014.

</string>

    <string name="special_duty1">

        <b>Special Duty Scaffolds</b>\n

Special duty scaffolds are scaffolds that have a specified design load for that scaffold only.
A special duty scaffold differs from other scaffold working platforms which are generally
rated as light, medium or heavy duty and have a standardised maximum load rating and
minimum dimensions. The following are some examples of common special duty scaffolds.\n

\n<b>Cantilever scaffold</b>\n

A cantilever scaffold is a scaffold supported by cantilevered load-bearing members.
The following risk control measures should be implemented for a cantilevered scaffold:\n

\n<b>•</b> Design and position cantilever beams in accordance with the engineer’s requirements
and the scaffolding plan.\n
\n<b>•</b> Ensure a competent person certifies that the supporting structure can support the
cantilevered scaffold.\n
\n<b>•</b> Use the following preferred methods for fixing the inboard length of the cantilevered
beam to the structure:\n
\n<b>(a)</b> Fix the beam to the floor below using a positive fixing e.g. a U-bolt fitted over the
beam and through the concrete floor slab.
\n<b>(b)</b> Use counterweights on the beam.
\n<b>(c)</b> Install props to the top of the beam and to the underside of the floor above, ensuring
the props are fixed to prevent dislodgement.\n

        \n© Commonwealth of Australia 2014.

    </string>

    <string name="special_duty2">

        <b>Hanging Bracket Scaffold</b>\n

Hanging bracket scaffolds are systems supported by frames on buildings or other structures.
Hanging brackets are sometimes in the shape of an upside down ‘L’, one arm of which is
fixed to a vertical surface, the other projecting horizontally to support scaffold planks.\n

\nOther hanging bracket scaffold systems may include horizontal members supported by
floors of buildings or other structures.\n

\nThe following risk control measures should be implemented for hanging bracket scaffolds:\n

\n<b>•</b> Provide a safe way for people installing hanging brackets to enter.\n
\n<b>•</b> Use connectors where two more scaffold planks sag unevenly and cause a tripping
hazard.\n
\n<b>•</b> Use an engineer to design hanging bracket scaffolds and their means of support—
engineering verification may be provided by calculation or load testing.\n
\n<b>•</b> The supporting structure should be able to support dead and live loads applied by the
hanging brackets.\n
\n<b>•</b> The spacing of brackets should not exceed the maximum plank spans specified by the
manufacturer.\n
\n<b>•</b> Planks may overlap planks on straight runs on hanging bracket scaffolds—where butting
of planks at a pair of brackets cannot be achieved—provided the overlap is at least
300 mm.\n

\nNote: This does not refer to overlap of planks on putlogs.

        \n© Commonwealth of Australia 2014.
    </string>

    <string name="special_duty3">

        <b>Spur Scaffold</b>\n

\nA spur scaffold is a scaffold supported by inclined load-bearing members.\n

\nThe following control measures should be implemented for a spur scaffold:\n

\n<b>•</b> Fix propping systems between the floor and ceiling at intervals to suit the spacing of the
standards within the scaffold.\n

\n<b>•</b> Provide suitable headstocks at the top of each propping system to distribute the loads
imposed.\n

\n<b>•</b> Ensure propping systems are securely tied together and braced.\n

\n<b>•</b> Brace spurs exceeding 1.8 metres in length in both directions at the centre unless
designed otherwise.\n

        \n© Commonwealth of Australia 2014.
    </string>

    <string name="trestle">
        <b>Trestle Scaffold</b>\n

A trestle scaffold is a scaffold assembled from
prefabricated trestles, braces and accessories.
Trestle scaffolds, for example ‘A-frame’ (see
Figure 2) and ‘H-frame’ trestle scaffolds, are
commonly used by bricklayers, plasterers and
painters and for general fit-out and finishing
work. Trestle scaffolds generally do not require
a licensed scaffolder to erect or dismantle.\n

\nTrestle scaffolds should be erected and
dismantled by a competent person in a
progressive way to ensure both the installer’s
safety and the stability of the overall structure.\n

\nBraces should be attached to the trestles
in accordance with the manufacturer’s or
supplier’s instructions. As the height of trestles
increase, there is a greater need to provide
lateral stability to the trestles.\n

\nA trestle scaffold should be stable and erected
on a suitable foundation to ensure it can safely
carry and distribute loads like materials and workers evenly to each trestle. Measures to
control instability and stop possible toppling can include using ties to a permanent structure
or using outriggers.\n

\nTrestle scaffolds should:\n

\n<b>•</b> have barriers or edge protection installed where the potential fall would result in injury
to people using the scaffold or the fall area contains hazards e.g. sharp objects like steel
reinforcing bars\n

\n<b>•</b> support the relevant live load or duty rating—not exceeding load limit
Note: The full width of a trestle should be fully planked, irrespective of the duty rating.\n

\n<b>•</b> have scaffold planks that are uniform and in a serviceable condition e.g. no splits, cracks,
knots or bends, overhang their end supports between 150–250 mm and are secured
against uplift\n

\n<b>•</b> have a horizontal work platform at least 450 mm wide. On sloping or uneven ground
use a trestle that incorporates height adjustment. Bricks or blocks should not be used as
soleplates\n

\n<b>•</b> have a safe means of entry and exit e.g. by secured ladders or from the building if
approximately level with the platform\n

\n<b>•</b> have a safe means to load material onto the working platform e.g. use mechanical means
or if this is not practicable, pass—do not throw—material up to the working platform, and\n

\n<b>•</b> not be used by multiple people in restricted work areas at the same time e.g. so as not
to overload 450 mm, 2 plank platforms.\n

\nMost bracing systems for tubular trestle scaffolds are manufactured from light materials
and are easily damaged by misuse or abuse so care should be taken during installation and
dismantling. Under no circumstances should anyone climb the braces or trestles.
Cross-braces on trestle scaffolding do not satisfy the requirements for edge protection.\n

        \n© Commonwealth of Australia 2014.
    </string>

    <string name="erect1">
<b>Scaffold erection</b>\n

The following safe work practices should be used
when erecting a scaffold:\n

\n<b>•</b> Develop and follow a methodical work sequence—e.g. in a SWMS or scaffolding plan.\n

\n<b>•</b> Scaffold fittings and other connections should be securely tightened where required.
Fittings should be in accordance with the manufacturer’s or designer’s specifications
and the scaffolding plan.\n

\n<b>•</b> Scaffolding including all bracing and ties, guy ropes or buttresses should be installed as
the scaffold is erected.\n

        \n<b>•</b> Consider using specifically designed loading platforms or back propping to prevent
overloading the building floor or the scaffold.\n

\n<b>•</b> Get certification from a competent person before erecting scaffold on awnings.\n

\n<b>•</b> Check live loads arising from the work of erecting or dismantling the scaffold are within
the specification for the final design—the number of workers on the scaffold at any one
time may need to be limited.\n

\n<b>•</b> Work from a full deck of planks whenever possible.\n

\n<b>•</b> Do not overload scaffold bays with scaffolding awaiting installation.\n

\n<b>•</b> Do not climb on guardrails to gain extra height.\n

\n<b>•</b> Do not climb on outside of scaffold.\n

\n<b>•</b> Implement measures to control the risk of a fall if the internal gap—the gap between
the inner edge of the length of the platform and the face of the building or structure
immediately beside the platform—on scaffolds including hanging bracket scaffolds is
greater than 225 mm. For example, install:\n

\n<b>(a)</b> edge protection, and
\n<b>(b)</b> extra scaffold planks to minimise the size of the internal gap.\n

\nAn example of scaffold erection is
shown in Figure 2. In this example
the scaffold is being erected against
an existing building so guardrails
are only needed on external faces.
Access ladders and toeboards have
been omitted for clarity.\n

\nAfter enough components of the
scaffold have been erected to
support it, immediately install:\n

\n<b>•</b> a platform at least 450 mm
wide along the full length of the
section of scaffold\n

\n<b>•</b> edge protection across the
space between the standards
forming the outer frame of the
scaffold at the level the scaffold
has reached, and\n

\n<b>•</b> a way to access the scaffold
e.g. temporary stairs or a ladder
to the level the scaffold has
reached.\n

\nBefore the next level of the scaffold
is erected, a platform should be
installed not more than two metres
below the position of the next level.

        \nWhen erecting scaffolding:\n

\n<b>•</b> A section of the platform may
be left open to allow the passing
of planks or other scaffolding
between levels.\n

\n<b>•</b> A platform may be removed
after work has started two levels
above the level from which the
platform is to be removed.\n

        \n<b>•</b> When installing or erecting scaffolds over or beside water, risk controls may include
alternative erection methods, for example prefabrication away from the water and
installation by crane.\n

\n<b>•</b> The scaffolding should be checked and any defective scaffolding should be clearly
marked with paint or tags so it is identified and can be removed from the work area to
prevent use.

        \n© Commonwealth of Australia 2014.

    </string>

<string name="dismatal">

    <b>Dismantling a Scaffold Safely</b>\n

The following safe work practices should be used when dismantling a scaffold:\n

\n<b>•</b> Edge protection and a way to enter the scaffold can be removed as the scaffold is
dismantled, provided it is removed at the last possible stage.\n

\n<b>•</b> Where possible a platform of at least 450 mm wide at the level the dismantling has
reached should be in place.\n

\n<b>•</b> Ensure when dismantling the scaffold the platform immediately below the level the worker
is standing on has a full set of planks across its width and is no lower than 2 metres.\n

\n<b>•</b> A section of the scaffold may be left open to allow the lowering of planks or other
scaffolding between levels.\n

\n<b>•</b> Scaffolding should never be dropped in an uncontrolled way when dismantling the scaffold.\n

    \n© Commonwealth of Australia 2014.

</string>

    <string name="alteration">
       <b>Altering a Scaffold</b>\n

When altering a scaffold you should:\n

\n<b>•</b> consult the scaffold designer before making alterations\n

\n<b>•</b> ensure scaffold alterations are in accordance with the scaffolding plan\n

\n<b>•</b> ensure alterations do not compromise the structural integrity of the scaffold, and\n

\n<b>•</b> ensure systems are in place to identify unauthorised interference with the scaffold
e.g. regular inspections.\n

        \n© Commonwealth of Australia 2014.

    </string>

    <string name="inspect_scaff">

        <b>Inspecting Scaffolds</b>\n

Procedures should be developed for inspecting and maintaining the scaffold and
scaffolding to ensure the scaffold is safe to use and remains in a safe condition.
For suspended, cantilevered, spur and hung scaffolds and any other scaffold from which
a person or thing could fall more than 4 metres:\n

\n<b>•</b> the scaffold must not be used unless there is written confirmation from a competent
person that they have inspected the scaffold and construction of the scaffold is
complete\n

\n<b>•</b> the scaffold and its supporting structure must be inspected by a competent person:\n

\n<b>(a)</b> before the scaffold is used after an incident has occurred that might affect the
stability of the scaffold
\n<b>(b)</b> before the scaffold is used after repairs
\n<b>(c)</b> at least every 30 days\n

\n<b>•</b> if an inspection indicates that a scaffold or its supporting structure creates a risk to
health or safety:\n

\n<b>(a)</b> any necessary repairs, alterations and additions must be made, and
\n<b>(b)</b> the scaffold and its supporting structure are inspected by a competent person
before the scaffold is used, and\n

\n<b>•</b> unauthorised access to the scaffold is prevented while the scaffold is incomplete or
unattended.\n

\nScaffolds with a fall risk of less than 4 metres should also be inspected before use and after
any incident, repair, alteration or addition.\n

Inspecting scaffolds and scaffolding at a workplace is particularly important when the
scaffold is in place for a long period of time.\n

        \n© Commonwealth of Australia 2014.
    </string>

    <string name="handover">
        <b>Handover Inspections</b>\n

Once a scaffold has been erected a handover inspection should be completed to check that
the scaffold is safe to use. Where written confirmation from a competent person is required
this usually takes the form of a handover certificate. (see link below)\n

\nIf alterations, repairs or additions to the scaffold are required a further inspection should be
completed and a new handover certificate provided.\n

\nThe handover certificate should be kept at the workplace until the scaffold has been
dismantled.\n

        \n© Commonwealth of Australia 2014.

    </string>

    <string name="post_handover">
        <b>Post Handover Inspections</b>\n

Regular post-handover inspections should be completed once a scaffold is in use. How often
these inspections are done will vary depending on the type and size of the scaffold, scaffold
use, workplace conditions, the weather and any risk of scaffold collapse.\n

\nScaffold inspections must be completed every 30 days for scaffolds with a fall risk of more
than 4 metres. The designer or supplier of the scaffold should be consulted on the intervals
for inspection when the scaffold is first installed.\n

\nIf an inspection identifies a problem with the scaffold, access to the scaffold must be
controlled and any necessary repairs, alterations and additions completed. Once the
work is complete the scaffold must be inspected again. Where written confirmation from
a competent person is required a new handover certificate should be provided.\n

\nRegular scaffold maintenance should also include inspections of stored scaffold components
as well as those in use. Scaffolding stored in areas exposed to the weather can become
corroded. Each item of scaffolding should be inspected before being incorporated into
a scaffold.\n

\nInspection records should be kept at the workplace or be readily accessible near the scaffold
should they be required. Inspection records should include the location, comments, date and
time of inspections, relevant design or specification reference and the person who carried
out the inspection.\n

        \n© Commonwealth of Australia 2014.

    </string>

    <string name="scaffolding_inspect">
<b>Scaffolding</b>\n

Suppliers and owners of plant must ensure, so far as is reasonably practicable, the plant is
without risk to health and safety when properly used. To identify defects, procedures for
regularly inspecting new and re-used scaffolding should be developed and implemented. If
any affected components are detected they should be repaired or disposed of and replaced
as required.\n

\nScaffolding should meet the requirements set out in the manufacturer’s or designer’s
specifications or relevant technical standards e.g. the strength of component material.
Scaffolding should be regularly inspected and maintained to ensure the continued structural
integrity of an erected scaffold.\n

        \n© Commonwealth of Australia 2014.

    </string>


    <!-- TODO: Remove or change this placeholder text -->
    <string name="hello_blank_fragment">Hello blank fragment</string>
</resources>
